<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-03-07T15:43:46+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Your awesome title</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Integrating Decentraland’s Estate in your Marketplace</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blockchain-integration/estates-marketplace-integrations/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Integrating Decentraland’s Estate in your Marketplace" /><published>2022-02-17T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2022-02-17T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blockchain-integration/estates-marketplace-integrations</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blockchain-integration/estates-marketplace-integrations/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="integrating-decentralands-estate-in-your-marketplace">Integrating Decentraland’s Estate in your Marketplace</h2>

<p>The Decentraland’s Estate is an ERC721 compliant NFT and runs in Ethereum Mainnet. Therefore a lot of third party marketplaces can trade them. In order to do so, this marketplace must follow
certain rules in order to make keep trades secure for the users.</p>

<p>As you may know, each <a href="https://docs.decentraland.org/decentraland/faq/#what-is-an-estate">Estate</a> is a group of <a href="https://docs.decentraland.org/decentraland/faq/#what-is-land">LANDs</a> and it have a <em>bytes</em> hash associated to the group that it call <em><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">fingerprint</code></em>. Everytime the Estate changes by adding or removing a LAND, its <em><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">fingerprint</code></em> changes too.</p>

<p>For marketplaces, especially the ones without an escrow system, it is 100% recommended to have a record of the Estate’s <em><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">fingerprint</code></em> when someone list it for sale or makes an offer. That way, when the order/offer is successfully executed, the current owner can’t change the estate by trying to front-run the order execution.</p>

<h2 id="example">Example</h2>

<h3 id="not-using-the-estate-fingerprint">Not using the Estate fingerprint</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Bob has the Estate1 with LAND (1,1) and (1,2). Estate1 fingerprint: hash1</li>
  <li>Bob adds the LAND (1,3) to Estate1. The Estate1 has the LANDs: (1,1), (1,2), and (1,3). Estate1 fingerprint: hash2 (Fingerprint changed)</li>
  <li>Bob removes the LAND (1,1) from Estate1. The Estate1 has the LANDs: (1,2) and (1,3). Estate1 fingerprint: hash3 (Fingerprint changed)</li>
  <li>Bob puts on sale the Estate1. The list is created onchain in the Ethereum mainnet with the Estate smart contract address, the Estate id, the price, and the expiration date.</li>
  <li>Alice sends a transaction to buy the Estate specifying the estate id and the price expected to pay.</li>
  <li>Bob detects that someone is trying to buy his Estate1 and sends a transaction with higher gas fees than Alice to remove the LANDs (1,2) and (1,3) from Estate1.</li>
  <li>Bob’s transactions is mined first. Estate1 has 0 LANDs. Estate1 fingerprint: hash4 (Fingerprint changed)</li>
  <li>Alice’s transaction is mined later. Alice bought the Estate1 with 0 LANDs on it. It means that Alice got front-runned (and stolen/scammed) by Bob.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="using-the-estate-fingerprint">Using the Estate fingerprint</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Bob has the Estate1 with LAND (1,1) and (1,2). Estate1 fingerprint: hash1</li>
  <li>Bob adds the LAND (1,3) to Estate1. The Estate1 has the LANDs: (1,1), (1,2), and (1,3). Estate1 fingerprint: hash2 (Fingerprint changed)</li>
  <li>Bob removes the LAND (1,1) from Estate1. The Estate1 has the LANDs: (1,2) and (1,3). Estate1 fingerprint: hash3 (Fingerprint changed)</li>
  <li>Bob puts on sale the Estate1. The list is created onchain in the Ethereum mainnet with the Estate smart contract address, the Estate id, the price, the expiration date.</li>
  <li>Alice sends a transaction to buy the Estate specifying the estate id, the price expected to pay, and <strong>the fingerprint she saw (hash3)</strong>.</li>
  <li>Bob detects that someone is trying to buy his Estate1 and sends a transaction with higher gas fees than Alice to remove the LANDs (1,2) and (1,3) from Estate1.</li>
  <li>Bob’s transactions is mined first. Estate1 has 0 LANDs. Estate1 fingerprint: hash4 (Fingerprint changed)</li>
  <li>Alice’s transaction is reverted because the smart contract checked that the fingerprint in the param that Alice sent didn’t match with the current Estate1 fingerprint (hash3 != hash4). This check prevented Alice to buy a non desired Estate.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="estate-smart-contract-interface">Estate Smart Contract Interface</h2>

<p>The Estate’s smart contract is compliant with a <a href="https://github.com/decentraland/land/blob/master/contracts/estate/EstateStorage.sol#L19">fingerprint interface</a>. In order to check if an order/offer for an estate is still valid or not, you can call the <em><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">verifyFingerprint(uint256 estateId, bytes fingerprint)</code></em> function implemented in the Estate smart contract. You can check a working production example <a href="https://github.com/decentraland/marketplace-contracts/blob/master/contracts/marketplace/MarketplaceV2.sol#L382">here</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blockchain-integration" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Important things to have in mind if you want to integrate the Decentraland's Estate in your marketplace]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/favicon.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/favicon.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Workspaces</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/development-guide/workspaces/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Workspaces" /><published>2022-02-08T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2022-02-08T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/development-guide/workspaces</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/development-guide/workspaces/"><![CDATA[<p>Run multiple Decentraland projects in preview by grouping these into a workspace. Run multiple adjacent scenes to see how they fit, or also run multiple <a href="/development-guide/smart-wearables/">smart wearables</a> together to see how they interact with each other and with different scenes.</p>

<p>Running multiple projects in a workspace provides a much more complete testing alternative, to ensure different content works well together.</p>

<h2 id="create-a-workspace">Create a workspace</h2>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Create a top-level folder to hold the workspace.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Inside this folder, add one folder at root level for each project you want to work with. You can drag in existing folders with scenes or smart wearables. For new folders, run <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">dcl init</code> inside each, to create a Decentraland project.</p>

    <blockquote>
      <p>Note: Make sure that the parcels on each of the scenes don’t overlap.</p>
    </blockquote>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Standing on the workspace folder, run the following, to create the necessary files:</p>

    <p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">dcl workspace init</code></p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>You can confirm that the projects are part of the workspace by running <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">dcl workspace ls</code>.</p>

<h2 id="run-a-workspace">Run a workspace</h2>

<p>Run <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">dcl start</code> on the root folder of the workspace. This runs all of the projects at the same time, viewable in a single preview window. This preview behaves just like when previewing a single scene.</p>

<p>Any smart wearables in the workspace are available to try on by looking for them in the backpack.</p>

<h2 id="add-projects">Add projects</h2>

<p>Once a workspace is created, you can add additional projects <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">dcl workspace add</code>, including the relative address of the folder you want to add. For example <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">dcl workspace add my-other-example</code>.</p>

<p>You can also add a project that is not inside the workspace folder, by using the absolute path.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Note: The folder must already contain a decentraland project initatied with <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">dcl init</code>. It can’t be an empty folder.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>You can also edit the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">dcl-workspace.json</code> file manually to add or remove projects. Modify the file to include the relative paths to each of the projects in the workspace in the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">folders</code> array.</p>

<div class="language-json highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="p">{</span><span class="w">
  </span><span class="nl">"folders"</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="p">[</span><span class="w">
    </span><span class="p">{</span><span class="w">
      </span><span class="nl">"path"</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="s2">"example-scene"</span><span class="w">
    </span><span class="p">},</span><span class="w">
    </span><span class="p">{</span><span class="w">
      </span><span class="nl">"path"</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="s2">"example-scene2"</span><span class="w">
    </span><span class="p">}</span><span class="w">
  </span><span class="p">]</span><span class="w">
</span><span class="p">}</span><span class="w">
</span></code></pre></div></div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="development-guide" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Run multiple DCL projects at a time]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/favicon.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/favicon.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Smart Wearables</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/development-guide/smart-wearables/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Smart Wearables" /><published>2022-02-02T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2022-02-02T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/development-guide/smart-wearables</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/development-guide/smart-wearables/"><![CDATA[<p>Smart wearables are a type of portable experience. Portable experiences are parts of the gameplay that players take with them as they move through the metaverse. For example, a player could take a snowball from your scene, walk away to another scene, and throw the snowball to another player who’s also playing the same game.</p>

<p>Smart wearables are portable experiences that are turned on when the player puts on a certain item of clothing. Smart wearables can grant players new abilities, like a jetpack that lets them fly, or add a new layer of content on top of the rest of the world, like randomly placing coins to be collected throughout the whole of genesis city.</p>

<h2 id="getting-started">Getting started</h2>

<p>To create a new smart wearable</p>

<ol>
  <li>Make sure you have the latest version of the CLI installed</li>
</ol>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">npm i -g decentraland@latest</code></p>

<ol>
  <li>Open a command line in a new folder and run</li>
</ol>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">dcl init</code></p>

<p>When prompted by the command, select <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">smart wearable (beta)</code></p>

<p>This command creates the basic files and structure for a new smart wearable. This folder is very similar to that of a Decentraland scene, but you will notice the following differences:</p>

<ul>
  <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">asset.json</code> includes all of the metadata for the portable experience</li>
  <li>There’s a placeholder 3d model (glasses.glb) and thumbnail (glasses.png) for a pair of dark glasses. You should replace these with the actual wearable you want to use</li>
  <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">scene.json</code> is a lot shorter, it doesn’t include properties that are irrelevant to a wearable, like parcels or spawn points</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="about-assetjson">About Asset.json</h2>

<p>The default <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">asset.json</code> file looks like this:</p>

<div class="language-json highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="p">{</span><span class="w">
  </span><span class="nl">"id"</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="err">&lt;random-id&gt;</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="w">
  </span><span class="nl">"assetType"</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="s2">"portable-experience"</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="w">
  </span><span class="nl">"name"</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="s2">"Portable Experience Example"</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="w">
  </span><span class="nl">"description"</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="s2">"My new Portable Experience"</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="w">
  </span><span class="nl">"category"</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="s2">"eyewear"</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="w">
  </span><span class="nl">"rarity"</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="s2">"mythic"</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="w">
  </span><span class="nl">"thumbnail"</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="s2">"glasses.png"</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="w">
  </span><span class="nl">"menuBarIcon"</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="s2">"glasses.png"</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="w">
  </span><span class="nl">"model"</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="s2">"glasses.glb"</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="w">
  </span><span class="nl">"bodyShape"</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="s2">"both"</span><span class="w">
</span><span class="p">}</span><span class="w">
</span></code></pre></div></div>

<p>The following fields are present in <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">asset.json</code>:</p>

<ul>
  <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">id</code>: The <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">dcl init</code> command generates a random value for this ID.</li>
</ul>

<blockquote>
  <p>NOTE: If you forked your project from an existing one, make sure the ID value is unique before publishing your wearable. Use <a href="https://www.uuidgenerator.net/">uuidgenerator.net</a> to generate a new random UUID</p>
</blockquote>

<ul>
  <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">assetType</code>: This field is required for the preview to identify this project as a portable experience.</li>
  <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">name</code>: The name for the wearable that users will see in the marketplace</li>
  <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">description</code>: The description of the wearable that users will see in the marketplace. Make sure you indicate what the smart wearable can do, as users of the marketplace will have no way to preview its functinality before buying it.</li>
  <li>
    <p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">category</code>: What wearable category to use. Possible values are:</p>

    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>‘eyebrows’</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>‘eyes’</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>‘facial_hair’</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>‘hair’</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>‘mouth’</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>‘upper_body’</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>‘lower_body’</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>‘feet’</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>‘earring’</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>‘eyewear’</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>‘hat’</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>‘helmet’</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>‘mask’</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>‘tiara’</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>‘top_head’</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>‘skin’</p>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">rarity</code>: The rarity supply of the token. Possible values are:
    <ul>
      <li>unique (1 copy)</li>
      <li>mythic (10 copies)</li>
      <li>legendary (100 copies)</li>
      <li>epic (1000 copies)</li>
      <li>uncommon (10.000 copies)</li>
      <li>common (100.000 copies)</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">thumbnail</code>: Image to use as thumbnail for the wearable, both in the backpack and the marketplace. This image should be at root level in your folder. The recommended image size is 256x256.</li>
  <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">menuBarIcon</code>: Image to use on the “experiences” menu, to represent this portable experience, to represent the portable experience. This image should be at root level in your folder. The recommended image size is 256x256.</li>
  <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">model</code>: The 3d model to use for the wearable. This file should be at root level in your folder.</li>
  <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">bodyShape</code>: The avatar body type that this wearable is compatible with. Possible values:
    <ul>
      <li>male</li>
      <li>female</li>
      <li>both</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<h2 id="the-preview">The Preview</h2>

<p>Running a preview of a portable experience is just like running that of a scene, simply run <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">dcl start</code>. If the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">asset.json</code> file is properly configured and the project is recognized as a portable experience, you’ll notice that all the visible around you are the default empty parcels. In this preview mode, you are not restricted to any set of parcels, you can add 3d models or sounds anywhere in the world.</p>

<h2 id="tips">Tips</h2>

<ul>
  <li>When positioning an entity, note that positions are global, relative to the 0,0 coordinates of Genesis Plaza.</li>
  <li>To react to nearby players:
    <ul>
      <li>use <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">getConnectedPlayers()</code> to know what players are already there, and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">onPlayerConnectedObservable</code> / `onPlayerDisconnectedObservable to track other players coming and going.</li>
      <li>Be mindful that the loading of the smart wearable, surrounding scenes and other players may occur in different orders depending on the situation. If the player enters Decentraland with the smart wearable already on, it’s likely that your portable experience will load before other players do. On the other hand, tf the player first loads into a scene and then puts on the wearable, it’s likely that other players will already be loaded by the time the portable experience starts running.</li>
      <li>Wait till the player is connected to an island inside their realm. Fetch the realm data and check for the ‘room’ field. If the ‘room’ field is null, the player is not yet connected to an island and other players won’t be loaded yet. You can periodically check this every 1 second till the ‘room’ field is present, and only initialize your logic then.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>To interact with surrounding scenes:
    <ul>
      <li>You can’t directly send any instructions to nearby scenes or other portable experiences, the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">messageBus</code> is currently sandboxed for each portable experience/scene.</li>
      <li>You can use an intermediate server to send information between the portable experience and a scene.</li>
      <li>If you do a raycast, you can detect hits against the colliders of entities from the surrounding scenes. This can tell you the exact hit location, normal direction, and even the entity name and mesh name of the 3d model.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Kill a portable experience: Run the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">kill()</code> method to self-terminate a portable experience.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="publish">Publish</h2>

<p>To publish your smart wearable:</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Make sure the information in <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">asset.json</code> is accurate. If you used another project as a starting point, make sure the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">id</code> is a unique identifier, not used by other wearables.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Run <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">dcl pack</code> on your project folder. This generates a <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">portable-experience.zip</code> file in your project folder.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<blockquote>
  <p>NOTE: The output of <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">dcl pack</code> will indicate the size of the uncompressed exported project, it must be under 2MB. If larger than that, it won’t be accepted by the builder.</p>
</blockquote>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Open the Builder, open the Collections tab, click + to upload a new wearable.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Drag your compressed <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">portable-expereince.zip</code> file into the Builder, verify that all the information is accurate.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<blockquote>
  <p>Note: If your wearable is an upper_body or a lower_body and meant to be unisex, you need to do a workaround (even if both body shapes use the same model):</p>
</blockquote>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>- Select only Male and complete the process
- Open the wearables in the editor, click the three dot options button, select “upload female representation”, and upload the 3d model for the female shape.
</code></pre></div></div>

<ol>
  <li>Open the editor and make sure the “hide” and “remove” categories are correctly set to disable other wearable categories when this wearable is on.</li>
  <li>Create a new collection with this and perhaps other wearables.</li>
  <li>Hit the 3 dots icon next to “Mint Items” and select “See in world”. This will open a tab with the explorer on ropsten, where you can try out all the wearables of your collection in Decentraland, and see how they behave in a more real scenario, for example running around Genesis Plaza.</li>
  <li>At this point, your wearable is ready to be published. We still don’t encourage creators to publish any smart wearables, as we’re still in experimental stages, reviewers from the committee have been instructed to not approve any smart wearables that don’t come from the foundation.</li>
</ol>

<blockquote>
  <p>Note: There will be a <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">dcl deploy</code> command in the future, to enable you to do this process without navigating the Builder UI.</p>
</blockquote>

<!--
## Restricted actions

To prevent abuse, certain features aren't permitted on portable experiences, or require adding a permission flag.

The following actions require special permissions

- Send HTTP requests
- Connect to a WebSockets server
... etc
-->

<h2 id="limitations">Limitations</h2>

<blockquote>
  <p>IMPORTANT: The entire smart wearable needs to fit within 2 MB. This includes the 3d model, thumbnail, code, libraries, sound files, additional 3d models, UI images, etc. This limit is for the uncompressed folder. The builder will not let you upload larger wearables than this.
To check the size of your portable experience, run <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">dcl pack</code>, the project size is specified in the output text of the command. You can also verify this by uncompressing the generated <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">portable-expereince.zip</code> file.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Smart wearables only run the portable experience for the player wearing the wearable. Other players don’t see the effects. For example, if the portable experience renders a pet that follows the player, other players around won’t see this pet.</p>

<p>Smart wearables only work when players have them on. For this reason, players can only have a limited number of activated smart wearables, and depending on what part of the body they take up, some will be incompatible with others. For example, you can’t have two hats at the same time, or a helmet and hair at the same time.</p>

<p>If a wearable is “hidden” but not “removed” by other wearables being worn, then the portable experience can still be on, even if the corresponding wearable is not visible.</p>

<h2 id="examples">Examples</h2>

<p><a href="https://github.com/decentraland-scenes/Portal-ble_experience">Portal-ble expoerence</a></p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/decentraland-scenes/Smart-wearable-graffitti">Graffiti</a></p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/decentraland-scenes/Smart-wearable-radio">Radio</a></p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/decentraland-scenes/Smart-wearable-raycast-test">Raycast test</a></p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/decentraland-scenes/Smart-wearable-realms-test">Realms test</a></p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/decentraland-scenes/Smart-wearable-rocket-board">Rocket board</a></p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/decentraland-scenes/Smart-wearable-Scarvenger-hunt">Scarvenger hunt</a></p>

<p>Xmas 2021:</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/nearnshaw/xmas-airdrops">Xmas airdrops</a></p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/decentraland-scenes/snowball-fight">Snowball fight</a></p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/decentraland-scenes/xmas-secret-santa">Secret Santa</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="development-guide" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Create wearables with interactive capabilities]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/favicon.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/favicon.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Requesting Grants</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/decentraland/requesting-grants/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Requesting Grants" /><published>2021-06-18T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2021-06-18T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/decentraland/requesting-grants</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/decentraland/requesting-grants/"><![CDATA[<p>To <a href="/decentraland/community-grants/">request a grant</a> from the Decentraland DAO, begin by navigating to <strong><a href="https://governance.decentraland.org">governance.decentraland.org</a></strong> and signing in with your wallet.</p>

<p>Click <strong>Submit a proposal</strong> and choose <strong>Grant request</strong> from the list of proposal categories. You will be presented with a form that you must complete before submitting your request.</p>

<h2 id="grant-proposal-forms">Grant proposal forms</h2>

<p>When you submit a grant request, you are expected to complete the proposal form to the best of your ability. Particular attention should be given to the abstract, description, specification, personnel, and roadmap sections. Failure to provide clear and relevant information may result in the rejection of your proposal by the community.</p>

<p>Following is an overview of the proposal form:</p>

<h4 id="category">Category</h4>

<p>Select the category that best describes your project. Currency, DAO grants will fund projects within four categories:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Community</li>
  <li>Content Creator</li>
  <li>Platform Contributor</li>
  <li>Gaming</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="tier">Tier</h4>

<p>Select the most appropriate tier for your grant request. Tiers enable the Decentraland Community to limit the size and scope of the grants that are funded by the DAO. The initial possible tiers are:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Tier 1:</strong> $500 - $1500 USD in MANA</li>
  <li><strong>Tier 2:</strong> $1500 - $3000 USD in MANA</li>
  <li><strong>Tier 3:</strong> $3000 - $5000 USD in MANA</li>
</ul>

<p>Tiers 1 and 2 are paid via a direct transfer to the beneficiary address provided within 7 days of a grant receiving approval from the DAO.</p>

<p>Tier 3 is paid via a vesting contract with a one month cliff.</p>

<h4 id="title">Title</h4>

<p>Provide a title that is concise and descriptive for your grant request. This title will appear as the header of your proposal’s detail page on <a href="governance.decentraland.org">governance.decentraland.org</a>, the proposal in Snapshot, and the Forum thread generated for your proposal.</p>

<h4 id="abstract">Abstract</h4>

<p>Use this space to provide a quick and easy to understand overview of your project. Your abstract should explain what problems your grant might solve, or what value it might provide to the greater community.</p>

<h4 id="grant-size">Grant size</h4>

<p>Enter the exact amount of funding you are requesting for your grant in USD. This amount should be within range for the Tier you’ve selected. If your grant is approved, it will be paid in MANA according to the current exchange rate between USD and MANA.</p>

<h4 id="beneficiary-address">Beneficiary address</h4>

<p>Enter an Ethereum address that you can use to receive the funds if your grant is approved.</p>

<h4 id="description">Description</h4>

<p>This is where you can provide a longer and more detailed description of your project.</p>

<h4 id="specification">Specification</h4>

<p>Here you can share a more detailed plan for what you would like to create or build. If there are any supporting assets or preliminary work, please share them here.</p>

<h4 id="personnel">Personnel</h4>

<p>If you are the only contributor to the project you would like to fund, enter some biographical information, making sure to include an overview of your skills and experience and why they are uniquely suited for your project. You are also strongly encouraged to provide links to a portfolio of previous work that is relevant to your proposed project.</p>

<p>If multiple people would contribute to your project, please share these details for each.</p>

<h4 id="roadmap-and-milestones">Roadmap and milestones</h4>

<p>Please share a realistic and achievable timeline for your project with discrete milestones. It is important that you publicly share progress toward each milestone in the Forum thread generated for your grant. Milestones should include concrete deliverables and dates, to make it easy for the community to compare your actual progress with your initial proposal.</p>

<h2 id="submitting-your-proposal">Submitting your proposal</h2>

<p>After filling out every field in the proposal form to the best of your abilities, click <strong>Submit proposal</strong>.</p>

<p>After submitting your proposal, a Forum thread will be generated automatically where the community can provide feedback on, or ask questions about, your project.</p>

<p>Grant requests remain open on the DAO for 7 days, during which the community can review and vote on your proposal.</p>

<h2 id="minimum-acceptance-thresholds">Minimum acceptance thresholds</h2>

<p>As has been <a href="https://governance.decentraland.org/en/proposal/?id=95141550-c3f4-11eb-b2bc-870b0f8c50b5">voted in place by the DAO</a>, grant requests cannot be approved by the DAO unless 1 million VP or more votes in <strong>For</strong> the request and the <strong>For</strong> votes have the majority.</p>

<p>Failure to reach at least 1 million VP, even if the <strong>For</strong> votes are in the majority, results in the rejection of the proposal. Grant requests may be resubmitted, so if you fail to obtain approval, you may revise and resubmit your proposal at a later date.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Decentraland" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How to request a grant from the DAO]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/favicon.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/favicon.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Receiving Grants</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/decentraland/receiving-grants/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Receiving Grants" /><published>2021-06-18T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2021-06-18T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/decentraland/receiving-grants</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/decentraland/receiving-grants/"><![CDATA[<p>If your <a href="/decentraland/community-grants/">grant request</a> was approved by the DAO, congratulations! Following is an overview of what happens when your grant is approved, the actions you need to take to receive your funding, and how you are expected to report your work to the community.</p>

<h2 id="receiving-your-mana">Receiving your MANA</h2>

<p>The process for receiving funds varies between the different grant tiers.</p>

<h2 id="tier-1-and-tier-2">Tier 1 and Tier 2</h2>

<p>Funds for grants in Tiers 1 and 2 are paid directly to the beneficiary address provided in the proposal form.</p>

<p>These transfers are initiated by the DAO Committee within 7 days of the grant’s approval by the DAO.</p>

<p>The funds are transferred in MANA equaling the USD amount specified in the grant proposal, according to the exchange rate at the time the transfer is initiated.</p>

<p>The beneficiary address provided within the grant proposal <strong>must be an Ethereum address</strong> that can receive MANA. Failure to provide a valid address may result in the irretrievable loss of the grant funds.</p>

<h2 id="tier-3">Tier 3</h2>

<p>Funds for grants in Tier 3 are made available to the beneficiary address provided in the proposal form via a vesting contract. <strong>It is the responsibility of the beneficiary to withdraw any vested funds from the contract.</strong></p>

<p>MANA in vesting contracts vests each second.</p>

<p>Vesting contracts have a one month cliff. MANA will still vest during this cliff, but it will not be available to the beneficiary until the end of the cliff.</p>

<p>After the cliff has been reached, the beneficiary may withdraw their vested funds as often as they wish, bearing in mind that they (the beneficiary) are responsible for paying the gas fee required for each withdrawal.</p>

<h2 id="reporting-your-progress">Reporting your progress</h2>

<p>You are expected to provide public reports on your progress on a schedule matching the milestones and roadmap detailed in your original grant proposal.</p>

<p>These updates are to be shared on the Forum thread generated for your grant request. These progress reports should be clear and concise, while still giving the community an accurate sense of how your project is progressing. Sharing screenshots or demos of your work goes a long way toward maintaining the trust of the community.</p>

<h2 id="revoked-grants">Revoked grants</h2>

<p>Currently, only grants with vesting contracts may be revoked. Conditions or behaviors that might lead to a grant being revoked include:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Failure to provide progress reports according to the roadmap and milestones listed in your grant proposal</li>
  <li>Providing progress reports showing work that does not meet the expectations set by your original grant proposal</li>
  <li>Providing work that violates either the <a href="https://decentraland.org/content">Content Policy</a>, <a href="https://decentraland.org/terms">Terms of Use</a>, or <a href="https://decentraland.org/ethics">Code of Ethics</a></li>
</ul>

<h2 id="what-happens-if-your-grant-is-revoked">What happens if your grant is revoked?</h2>

<p>If your grant is revoked before the end of your vesting contract’s cliff, then you will not receive any of your grant funds.</p>

<p>If your grant is revoked after the end of your contract’s cliff, then you will still be able to withdraw any funds that have already vested.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Decentraland" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How to receive your grant]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/favicon.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/favicon.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Community Grants</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/decentraland/community-grants/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Community Grants" /><published>2021-06-18T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2021-06-18T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/decentraland/community-grants</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/decentraland/community-grants/"><![CDATA[<p>The Decentraland DAO possesses a <a href="/decentraland/the-dao-fund/">MANA fund</a> that has been set aside to help sponsor and facilitate the continual growth of the Decentraland platform. One avenue used by the DAO to achieve these goals is a grants program that was <a href="https://governance.decentraland.org/en/proposal/?id=b265e3e0-bcb0-11eb-a871-a927ffd81f49">voted in place by the DAO</a>.</p>

<p>This grants program allows any member of the community to request funding to help reimburse their efforts in community building and education, creating 3D content for the world, or implementing new features and improvements to the platform.</p>

<p>Grants can be requested by <a href="/decentraland/requesting-grants/">completing a proposal</a> form within the <a href="https://governance.decentraland.org">DAO</a>. If approved by the community, then the <a href="/decentraland/how-does-the-dao-work/#dao-committee">DAO Committee</a> will execute the <a href="/decentraland/receiving-grants/">transfer of funds</a> to the grant beneficiary by means of a one-time transfer, or a vesting contract.</p>

<h2 id="grant-categories">Grant categories</h2>

<p>Grant requests can fall under one of four broad categories: <strong>Community</strong>, <strong>Content Creator</strong>, <strong>Platform Contributor</strong>, or <strong>Gaming</strong>. These four categories represent areas of Decentraland that benefit most from community contributions.</p>

<h2 id="community">Community</h2>

<p>Growing, educating, moderating, and maintaining a healthy community of players, creators, and developers is important to Decentraland’s success. Grants under this category may fund activity such as:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Community education</li>
  <li>Outreach and event organization</li>
  <li>Moderation</li>
</ul>

<p>Projects might also include creating documentation, tutorials, videos, or other forms of content intended to educate and support the community.</p>

<h2 id="content-creator">Content Creator</h2>

<p>Filling the metaverse with engaging and immersive content takes time and effort from skilled, independent technical artists. Grants in this category help to support artists to create scenes and models for Decentraland. Applicants to this category must provide portfolios of related work within their grant requests for the community to review.</p>

<h2 id="platform-contributor">Platform Contributor</h2>

<p>Decentraland is an open source platform with many moving parts. Grants within the Builder category should motivate and reward impactful contributions from developers and engineers in the form of:</p>

<ul>
  <li>New features</li>
  <li>Bug or vulnerability fixes</li>
  <li>Other improvements to existing code</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="gaming">Gaming</h2>

<p>Engaging experiences in Decentraland often take the form of games, especially multiplayer games. This category bridges the Creator and Platform Contributor categories by funding individuals and teams committed to building complete games for Decentraland.</p>

<h2 id="grant-tiers">Grant tiers</h2>

<p>Grants may be requested for any amount within one of three possible tiers, regardless of the grant category. For example, you may request a Content Creator grant in either Tier 1, Tier 2, or Tier 3.</p>

<p>The specific tiers, and their ranges, are:</p>

<h4 id="tier-1">Tier 1</h4>

<ul>
  <li>$500 - $1500 USD in MANA</li>
  <li>One-time payment</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="tier-2">Tier 2</h4>

<ul>
  <li>$1500 - $3000 USD in MANA</li>
  <li>One-time payment</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="tier-3">Tier 3</h4>

<ul>
  <li>$3000 - $5000 USD in MANA</li>
  <li>Up to a 3 month vesting contract with a one month cliff</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="when-are-payments-made-for-each-tier">When are payments made for each tier?</h2>

<h4 id="tier-1-and-tier-2">Tier 1 and Tier 2</h4>

<p>Funds for grants in Tiers 1 or 2 are transferred directly to the beneficiary address within a week of the grant’s approval from the DAO.</p>

<h4 id="tier-3-1">Tier 3</h4>

<p>Funds for grants in Tier 3 are made available to the beneficiary address via vesting contracts. These contracts vest every second, and have a one month cliff. After the cliff, the owner of the beneficiary address may withdraw the vested MANA. Past the cliff, the beneficiary may withdraw any newly vested MANA.</p>

<h2 id="grant-requirements">Grant requirements</h2>

<ul>
  <li>Any work funded by the DAO must comply with the Decentraland <a href="https://decentraland.org/content">Content Policy</a>, <a href="https://decentraland.org/terms">Terms of Use</a>, and <a href="https://decentraland.org/ethics">Code of Ethics</a>.</li>
  <li>Regardless of category, each grant proposal must include clearly defined and measurable outcomes.</li>
  <li>Grant recipients must provide regular and thorough reports on their project’s progress for the community to review. These reports may be shared through the Decentraland Forum. Failure to provide these reports may result in the removal of grant funding.</li>
  <li>Failure to provide the pre-established outcomes, as well as to provide clear reports on the advances and milestones will result in the removal of the grant funding.</li>
  <li>Grants with one-time payments are to be transferred upon the DAO’s approval of the grant.</li>
  <li>Grants with vesting contracts have a one month cliff beginning 7 days after the grant’s approval in the DAO.</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Decentraland" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[An overview of community grants]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/favicon.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/favicon.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Creating Wearables</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/decentraland/creating-wearables/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Creating Wearables" /><published>2021-05-31T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2021-05-31T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/decentraland/creating-wearables</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/decentraland/creating-wearables/"><![CDATA[<h3 id="what-are-wearables">What are wearables?</h3>

<p>Wearables are the different clothing items, accessories, and body features that can be used to customize the appearance of a Decentraland avatar. While there are some default wearables available to all users, Decentraland also supports the use of custom wearables. These custom wearables can be created by both brands and users, and are often distributed in competitions and giveaways. Decantraland’s growing marketplace for user-generated content also includes support for wearables, which can be bought, sold, or traded as NFTs (non-fungible tokens).</p>

<p>There’s a growing range of available wearables including cyberpunk themed sneakers, fashionable jackets, fun tophats, and more! All of these stylistic choices give users an exciting and meaningful way to invest in, and express, their own unique personalities. By allowing wearables to be minted, and then sold, as NFTs, Decentraland provides content creators with a fun way to monetize their creative work.</p>

<p>This guide introduces the basics of creating custom 3D models for Decentraland wearables. It explains how the Decentraland “avatar system” works, and it illustrates how to properly model your own wearables.</p>

<p><strong>Note: this guide assumes that you already have some basic to intermediate knowledge of 3D modeling. If you’re new to 3D modeling, <a href="/3d-modeling/3d-models/">start here</a>.</strong></p>

<h3 id="the-decentraland-avatar-system">The Decentraland Avatar System</h3>

<p>The Decentraland “avatar system” is the broad collection of different body components and subcomponents that can be decorated with custom wearables. These components are:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Body shape</li>
  <li>Head
    <ul>
      <li>Head shape</li>
      <li>Eyebrows</li>
      <li>Eyes</li>
      <li>Mouth</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Upper body</li>
  <li>Lower body</li>
  <li>Feet</li>
</ul>

<h4 id="body-shape">Body shape</h4>

<p>The basic form of an avatar. Wearables can be assigned to one, or both, body shapes. Currently, there are two body shapes: A or B.</p>

<p><img src="/images/media/creating-wearables-images/creating-wearables-1.png" alt="" /></p>

<h4 id="head">Head</h4>

<p>The head includes several different meshes:</p>

<p><strong>Head Shape</strong><br />
This is the base mesh of the head on which all other head features attach to.</p>

<p><strong>Eyebrow</strong><br />
The Eyebrow mesh functions as a transparency mask. It is used to create different eyebrow styles.</p>

<p><strong>Eye Mesh</strong><br />
The Eye mesh functions as a transparency mask, and is used to create different eye styles.</p>

<p><strong>Mouth</strong><br />
The mouth mesh functions as a transparency mask, and is used to create different mouth styles.</p>

<p><img src="/images/media/creating-wearables-images/creating-wearables-2.png" alt="" /></p>

<h4 id="upper-body">Upper Body</h4>

<p>The upper body, or torso, of an avatar includes the arms and hands. All upper body wearables are applied to the entire torso.</p>

<p><img src="/images/media/creating-wearables-images/creating-wearables-3.png" alt="" /></p>

<h4 id="lower-body">Lower Body</h4>

<p>The lower body includes the pelvis, legs, and ankles of an avatar.</p>

<p><img src="/images/media/creating-wearables-images/creating-wearables-4.png" alt="" /></p>

<h4 id="feet">Feet</h4>

<p>Just the feet! All boots, shoes, sandals, socks, etc. are applied to the feet, not the lower body.</p>

<p><img src="/images/media/creating-wearables-images/creating-wearables-5.png" alt="" /></p>

<h3 id="wearable-categories">Wearable Categories</h3>

<p>Each wearable has a specific category that determines which body part in the avatar system (e.g. head, upper body, etc.) the wearable will be applied to. Certain wearables will impact whether or not other wearables are rendered, depending on the specific category. Some wearables will entirely replace others with sometimes unexpected and surprising results. See the list below for details.</p>

<p>The different categories are:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Body_shape:</strong> Replaces the entire avatar’s body.</li>
  <li><strong>Skin:</strong> Replaces the entire avatar (head, upper body, lower body and feet except accesories)</li>
  <li><strong>Hat:</strong> Replaces the avatar’s hair. For hats that leave some hair exposed, it must be attached to the hair in the mesh to prevent the avatar from going bald whenever they put on their hat.</li>
  <li><strong>Helmet:</strong> Overrides the avatar’s entire head, replacing both hair and facial_hair.</li>
  <li><strong>Hair:</strong> Replaces an avatar’s hat.</li>
  <li><strong>Facial_hair:</strong> facial hair won’t replace or override any other wearables.</li>
  <li><strong>Head:</strong>
    <ul>
      <li>Mouth</li>
      <li>Eyes</li>
      <li>Eyebrows</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong>Upper_body</strong></li>
  <li><strong>Lower_body</strong></li>
  <li><strong>Feet</strong></li>
</ul>

<p>There are also accessories that can be applied to different areas of an avatar. Some of these accessories can impact other wearables. The accessories are:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Mask:</strong> Replaces helmet, tiara, eye_wear and it will override facial_hair.</li>
  <li><strong>Eye_wear:</strong> Replaces helmet and mask.</li>
  <li><strong>Earring:</strong> Replaces helmet.</li>
  <li><strong>Tiara:</strong> Replaces mask and helmet.</li>
  <li><strong>Top_head:</strong> This is rendered on the top of an avatar’s hard. For example, an angel’s halo.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="building-3d-models-for-wearables">Building 3D models for wearables</h3>

<p>Let’s start to create some wearables!</p>

<p>To ensure that Decentrand runs smoothly for all users, it is important to create wearable models without using too many triangles. The goal is to keep models as simple as possible so that they can easily be rendered, without sacrificing too much detail.</p>

<p>The same goes for textures. It’s critical that we use as few textures as possible.</p>

<p>There are limits for the number of triangles and textures that can be used for each wearable or accessory:</p>

<ul>
  <li>No more than 1.5K triangles per wearable</li>
  <li>No more than 500 triangles per accessories</li>
  <li>No more than 2 textures (at a resolution of 512x512px or lower) per wearable. All textures must be square.</li>
  <li>In the case of skin wearable, the amount of tris allowed are 5k and 5 textures.</li>
</ul>

<p>Before you get started, download the example files for reference meshes and textures.</p>

<h4 id="upper-body-lower-body-and-feet">Upper body, Lower body, and Feet</h4>

<p>After downloading the example files, load the models into your 3D editor, like Blender.</p>

<p>You’ll notice that each model contains 7 different meshes related to an armature. These meshes represent the head, eyebrows, eyes, mouth, upper body, lower body and feet. You can use these example models as a reference and starting point for your own custom wearable.</p>

<p><strong>Important: Do not modify the “cuts” or the “stitches” between categories (unless you want to create an unusual “floating head” effect or something similar).</strong></p>

<p>You’ll also notice that each category has caps, making them “water tight”. These caps exist to prevent unsightly glitches if there are any animation clipping problems due to bad skin weighting. It’s best to leave these caps on.</p>

<p><img src="/images/media/creating-wearables-images/creating-wearables-6.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>There are two basic materials for avatar models. One is the material used for the wearable itself and the other one is used for the skin.</p>

<p><img src="/images/media/creating-wearables-images/creating-wearables-7.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>Each base mesh comes with its own skin texture.</p>

<p><img src="/images/media/creating-wearables-images/creating-wearables-8.png" alt="" />
<em>Skin for Avatar Shape A</em></p>

<p><img src="/images/media/creating-wearables-images/creating-wearables-9.png" alt="" />
<em>Skin for Avatar Shape B</em></p>

<p>You’ll notice that each skin texture is rendered grayscale in your editor. This allows us to tint the skin later in the avatar editor according to the user’s preference.</p>

<p><img src="/images/media/creating-wearables-images/creating-wearables-10.png" alt="" /></p>

<p><strong>Important: always preserve the UV mapping for any body part left exposed by a wearable, like the bottom of the legs left exposed by shorts and skirts. We want to leave any skin material meshes unmodified so that the user’s skin tone is rendered correctly.</strong></p>

<p><img src="/images/media/creating-wearables-images/creating-wearables-11.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>We want to leave the skin mesh alone and use the default AvatarWearable_MAT texture provided in the example files whenever possible to select colors for our wearables. This will guarantee that your wearables are performant. However, you can create custom textures for our wearables! It’s always best to use a single, very small, texture file for each wearable.</p>

<p><img src="/images/media/creating-wearables-images/creating-wearables-12.png" alt="" /></p>

<h4 id="eyebrows-eyes-and-mouth">Eyebrows, Eyes and Mouth</h4>

<p>These meshes work with a transparent shader so you don’t have to do anything aside from creating your own png texture for the new eyebrow, eye, or mouth style you want and placing it correctly into the UV map. These textures should be 256x256px and need to have, of course, an alpha channel (for transparency).</p>

<p>Here are some example png textures:</p>

<p><img src="/images/media/creating-wearables-images/creating-wearables-13.png" alt="" />
<em>Eyes</em></p>

<p><img src="/images/media/creating-wearables-images/creating-wearables-14.png" alt="" />
<em>Eyebrows</em></p>

<p><img src="/images/media/creating-wearables-images/creating-wearables-15.jpg" alt="" />
<em>Eyebrows</em></p>

<p><img src="/images/media/creating-wearables-images/creating-wearables-16.png" alt="" />
<em>Mouth</em></p>

<p><img src="/images/media/creating-wearables-images/creating-wearables-17.jpg" alt="" />
<em>Mouth</em></p>

<p><strong>Nodes:</strong><br />
To visualize the final result you’ll need to use these nodes (in Blender):</p>

<p><img src="/images/media/creating-wearables-images/creating-wearables-18.png" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="/images/media/creating-wearables-images/creating-wearables-19.png" alt="" /></p>

<p><strong>Masks:</strong><br />
You will notice that the Avatar Editor has different color options users can choose from when selecting different wearables.</p>

<p><img src="/images/media/creating-wearables-images/creating-wearables-20.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>These color choices are applied to a specific mask in the wearable.</p>

<p><img src="/images/media/creating-wearables-images/creating-wearables-21.png" alt="" />
<em>Eyes Mask</em></p>

<p><img src="/images/media/creating-wearables-images/creating-wearables-22.png" alt="" />
<em>Eyes Base</em></p>

<p>The black area in the image on the left (Eyes Mask) indicates the area of the texture on the right (Eyes Base) that will be colored. It’s important to remember that irises always have a grey band scale (if the iris is pure black, the tint isn’t going to work).</p>

<h3 id="hair-and-facial-hair">Hair and Facial Hair</h3>

<p>There are two important things to remember when creating custom hair wearables.</p>

<p>First, try to follow the shape of the head. You can always refer to the head mesh provided in the example files if you need a place to start.</p>

<p><img src="/images/media/creating-wearables-images/creating-wearables-23.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>Second, if you want users to be able to change the color of your custom hair or facial hair using the avatars editor, then you must paint the hair in grayscale. Lower shades of gray will appear darker and higher shades of gray will appear brighter, but always in the color selected by the user in the avatar editor.</p>

<h3 id="skin-weighting">Skin Weighting</h3>

<p>Skin weighting is the process of determining which bones in the avatar’s rigging affect which wearables during an animation.</p>

<p>When skin weighting our new wearables, there are several considerations we need to keep in mind.</p>

<p>Each asset must be weighted to the full skeleton. For example, an upper body asset will look like this when applying skin weights:</p>

<p><img src="/images/media/creating-wearables-images/creating-wearables-24.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>Wearables that meet at intersections between body parts must be fully weighted to the same bone. For example, in these two green zones, the vertices in the neck need to be fully weighted to the “Neck” bone only.</p>

<p><img src="/images/media/creating-wearables-images/creating-wearables-25.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>The “key” bones to use when skin weighting are:</p>

<p><strong>Head Bone:</strong> for the hair, earrings, tiaras, eyes, eyebrows, mouth and any accessory that needs to follow the head’s movement.</p>

<p><strong>Neck Bone:</strong> for the main head and upper body’s intersecting vertices.</p>

<p><strong>Hips Bone:</strong> for the upper body and lower body’s intersecting vertices.</p>

<p><strong>Right Leg and Left Leg Bones:</strong> for the lower body and feet intersecting vertices.</p>

<p>If you keep these guidelines in mind when skinning your avatar meshes, everything will work as with the native avatars.</p>

<p>Remember, you can use any bone to influence any mesh’s vertices! For example, you could create a new foot mesh for a tall pair of boots, and skin weight the top of the boot to the “Leg Bones”. Or, you could create some long hair and use the “Shoulder” or “Spine” bones to influence the hair when the avatar moves around.</p>

<h3 id="resources">Resources</h3>

<p>In this shared folder you can find base models, textures, and various other resources, including examples of fully-created wearables. Feel free to leverage these resources when creating your own.</p>

<p><a href="https://drive.google.com/drive/u/1/folders/12hOVgZsLriBuutoqGkIYEByJF8bA-rAU">Wearables Reference Models</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Decentraland" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tips and guidelines for creating Decentraland wearables]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/favicon.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/favicon.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Wearables Overview</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/decentraland/wearables-overview/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wearables Overview" /><published>2021-05-31T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2021-05-31T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/decentraland/wearables-overview</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/decentraland/wearables-overview/"><![CDATA[<p>Wearables are the various items of clothing, accessories, and body features that can be used to customize the appearance of a Decentraland avatar. There is a selection of default wearables that are freely available to all avatars, but Decentraland also supports the creation and use of custom wearables that are represented by non-fungible tokens (or NFTs). This allows a finite amount of different wearables to be created, or minted, on the blockchain, similar to the LAND.</p>

<p>By default, Decentraland Wearables are minted on the Polygon/Matic sidechain so users can mint, buy, sell, or transfer items without having to pay gas fees.</p>

<p><strong>Wearables are organized into different categories, depending on what part of an avatar they modify:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Body shape (the shape of the entire avatar)</li>
  <li>Hat</li>
  <li>Helmet</li>
  <li>Hair</li>
  <li>Facial hair</li>
  <li>Head</li>
  <li>Upper body (e.g. jacket or shirt)</li>
  <li>Lower body (e.g. pants or shorts)</li>
  <li>Feet</li>
  <li>Skin</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Wearables can also include accessories that are applied to different parts of an avatar’s body:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>Mask</li>
  <li>Eye wear</li>
  <li>Earring</li>
  <li>Tiara (a crown, or other accessory that sits on top of the head)</li>
  <li>Top-head (e.g. a halo, or other effect applied to the head)</li>
</ul>

<p>For a detailed description of each category, and how items within each category interact or replace one another, see <a href="/decentraland/creating-wearables/">Creating Wearables</a>.</p>

<h3 id="collections--items">Collections &amp; Items</h3>

<p>Wearables exist as individual <strong>items</strong> that can be grouped into <strong>collections</strong>.</p>

<h4 id="items">Items</h4>

<p>Remember how wearables are represented by non-fungible tokens (NFTs)? Well, each wearable <strong>item</strong> can be minted to create multiple NFTs of that same item, to a limit according to the item’s rarity (the rarer the item, the fewer NFTs you can mint). Items are often referred to as the “representations” of the wearable.</p>

<p>Items cannot be bought or sold, only the NFTs that have been minted from items. Also, individual items cannot be published on their own; they must be part of a collection.</p>

<h4 id="collections">Collections</h4>

<p><strong>Collections</strong> exist to help creators organize and manage their items before publication.</p>

<p>For example, let’s say we create a blue t-shirt and a red t-shirt. We can create a new collection called “Summer T-Shirts”, and then add our two shirts to that collection. After publishing our collection, we can then mint copies of the red and blue shirts to share, trade, or sell.</p>

<p>The following documentation only covers the <strong>Wearables Editor</strong>: the tool used to upload, add metadata to, and publish custom items and collections of items.</p>

<p>For documentation covering other aspects of wearables, see the following resources:</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="/decentraland/creating-wearables/">Creating Wearables</a></li>
  <li><a href="/decentraland/publishing-wearables/">Publishing Wearables</a></li>
  <li><a href="/decentraland/curation-committee/">Curation Committee</a></li>
  <li><a href="/decentraland/wearables-editor-user-guide/">Editor User Guide</a></li>
</ul>

<p>The following shared folder contains example wearables, base models, textures and other resources you can use:</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="https://drive.google.com/drive/u/1/folders/12hOVgZsLriBuutoqGkIYEByJF8bA-rAU">Wearables Reference Models</a></li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Decentraland" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[An overview of wearable NFTs for Decentraland]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/favicon.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/favicon.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Wearables Editor User Guide</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/decentraland/wearables-editor-user-guide/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wearables Editor User Guide" /><published>2021-05-31T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2021-05-31T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/decentraland/wearables-editor-user-guide</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/decentraland/wearables-editor-user-guide/"><![CDATA[<h3 id="what-is-the-wearables-editor">What is the Wearables Editor?</h3>

<p>The Wearables Editor is a tool within Decentraland’s Builder that allows you to upload, add metadata to, and publish your own custom wearables.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Remember: these docs don’t explain how to create the models, meshes, and textures that make up wearables, they just explain how to use the Wearables Editor to upload and publish your wearables. For an intro on the actual wearable creation process, <a href="/decentraland/creating-wearables/">start here</a>.</p>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="logging-in">Logging in</h3>

<p>To start uploading and publishing your wearables, navigate to <strong><a href="https://builder.decentraland.org">builder.decentraland.org</a></strong>.</p>

<p>Click <strong>Sign in</strong>, and then <strong>Connect</strong> to log in with your Metamask or Fortmatic wallet. After signing in, click the <strong>Collections</strong> tab.</p>

<h3 id="uploading-wearables">Uploading wearables</h3>

<p>If you haven’t uploaded any items yet, click <strong>New Item</strong> or <strong>New Collection</strong> to get started. If you’ve already uploaded some wearables, you can either edit them by clicking on the item or collection and then clicking <strong>Edit</strong>, or you can upload new wearables by clicking the <strong>+</strong> icon next to the Open Editor button.</p>

<h4 id="creating-a-collection">Creating a collection</h4>

<p>When creating a collection, first enter the name you would like to give your collection and click <strong>Create</strong>. After creating your collection, you can begin adding items.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The name of your collection cannot be changed after publication!</p>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>You can add as many items as you want until you publish your collection.</strong> Always remember, you cannot add, remove, or change the rarity of items in published collections.</p>

<p>To add an item to your new collection, select the collection, click <strong>New Item</strong>, and select your wearable files.</p>

<h4 id="uploading-an-item">Uploading an item</h4>

<p>When uploading an item you can either browse your computer to find the file you want, or you can click and drag your file right into the editor. For an overview of the 3D file types supported in Decentraland, see <a href="/3d-modeling/3d-models/">3D Model Essentials</a>.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Wearable items cannot currently exceed 2MB.</strong></p>
</blockquote>

<p>After uploading your file, you will be prompted to enter some descriptive information:</p>

<p><strong>Body shape</strong><br />
You can select which body shape your wearable is modeled for. The shape can be either A, B, or both. Wearables that are set to Shape A can only be worn by wearables with Body Shape A, while wearables set to Shape B can only be worn by avatars with Body Shape B. If you set the shape to Both, then avatars of both shapes can wear your wearable.</p>

<p><strong>Name</strong><br />
The name you would like to give your wearable.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The name of your collection cannot be changed after publication!</p>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>Rarity</strong><br />
The rarity of your wearable determines the total number of NFTs that may be minted based on your item. The rarities and the maximum number of NFTs that you may mint for each are:</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th>Rarity</th>
      <th>Limit</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>Unique</td>
      <td>1</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Mythic</td>
      <td>10</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Legendary</td>
      <td>100</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Epic</td>
      <td>1000</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Rare</td>
      <td>5000</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Uncommon</td>
      <td>10000</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Common</td>
      <td>100000</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p> </p>

<p><strong>Category</strong><br />
Wearables are organized into different categories, depending on what part of an avatar they modify. Select the appropriate category for your item:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Earring</li>
  <li>Eyewear</li>
  <li>Facial Hair</li>
  <li>Feet</li>
  <li>Hair</li>
  <li>Hat</li>
  <li>Helmet</li>
  <li>Lower Body</li>
  <li>Mask</li>
  <li>Upper Body</li>
  <li>Tiaras</li>
  <li>Top Head <em>(Top Head wearables can be either an item of effect that is applied to the top of the head, like an angel’s halo.)</em></li>
  <li>Skin</li>
</ul>

<p>When you’re finished entering your descriptive metadata, click <strong>Create</strong>.</p>

<h3 id="editing-items">Editing items</h3>

<p>To edit your items, navigate to the <a href="https://builder.decentraland.org">Builder</a> and select the <strong>Collections</strong> tab. Here, you’ll find all of your wearable collections and items. You can edit an individual item by clicking on the item, and then clicking <strong>Edit</strong>. To edit an item that is part of a collection, first select the collection, and then the item within the collection you’d like to edit.</p>

<h4 id="details">Details</h4>

<p>The item details list the number of triangles, materials, and textures that make up your wearable. It is recommended that you do not exceed the following limits when creating wearables:</p>

<ul>
  <li>1500 triangles per wearable (except skin category)</li>
  <li>500 triangles per accessory</li>
  <li>2 square textures of 512x512px (or lower)</li>
  <li>5k triangles for skin category and 5 textures of 512x512px (or lower).</li>
</ul>

<p>If the number of triangles and textures exceeds these guidelines, you can click the pencil icon to upload a new model, or “representation” of your wearable with lower triangle/texture counts. You can also change the preview image by clicking the camera icon when hovering over the preview thumbnail.</p>

<h4 id="basics">Basics</h4>

<p>This is the basic metadata you entered when you first uploaded your item. You can edit this information at any time leading up to the moment you publish your item within a collection.</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Name -</strong> the name of your item, this will be displayed when distributing your wearable on the marketplace</li>
  <li><strong>Description -</strong> a brief statement describing your item, this is displayed when distributing your wearable on the marketplace</li>
  <li><strong>Category -</strong> the component of an avatar’s body that your wearable modifies</li>
  <li><strong>Rarity -</strong> the rarity determines the maximum number of NFTs you will be able to mint of your wearable after publication. <em>This is the only property that cannot be modified after publishing a collection.</em></li>
</ul>

<h4 id="overrides">Overrides</h4>

<p>Overrides determine what other wearable categories your item will either replace, or hide. When setting overrides, you simply select a wearable category from the dropdown menu to add it to the override. You can add multiple categories to each override.</p>

<p><strong>Replaces</strong><br />
Any items within the categories added to this override will be unequipped from a users’ avatar when they equip your item. A user would have to re-equip any “replaced” items after unequipping your item. This does not delete items, it only unequips them.</p>

<p><strong>Hides</strong><br />
Any items within the categories added to this override will only be hidden (they won’t be rendered) when a user equips your item. When a user unequips your item, the hidden items will be rendered again automatically.</p>

<h4 id="tags">Tags</h4>

<p>Tags are simply descriptive words that users can use when searching or filtering for items. These could be relevant to competitions or events!</p>

<h3 id="custom-thumbnails">Custom thumbnails</h3>

<p>You can upload your own custom thumbnails for wearables in your collections. To upload a custom thumbnail image, navigate to the Wearables Editor and open the item you want to add a thumbnail for. Click <strong>Edit</strong> and then click on the thumbnail image under details to upload an image from your computer (a camera icon will appear when you hover over the thumbnail).</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Thumbnails must be 256px by 256px with transparent backgrounds. Collections containing thumbnails without transparent backgrounds will not be accepted by the Curation Committee.</p>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="setting-the-price-for-items">Setting the price for items</h3>

<p>Items that are included in a collection can include prices that you set for their primary sale.</p>

<p>To set the price of a wearable, navigate to the <a href="https://builder.decentraland.org">Builder</a> and select the <strong>Collections</strong> tab. Then click on the collection containing your items you want to price.</p>

<p>For each item in the list, click <strong>Set Price</strong>.</p>

<h4 id="price">Price</h4>

<p>The price that a user will have to pay in a primary purchase (the first purchase after minting) for your item. Prices are set in MANA. Remember that when you mint wearables, they are minted directly on Matic/Polygon. When a user purchases your item, the transaction will be conducted in Matic/Polygon MANA.</p>

<h4 id="beneficiary">Beneficiary</h4>

<p>The Ethereum address that will receive the MANA in a primary sale of your wearable. You can use any Ethereum address you like. To automatically fill in the address you’ve logged in with, click <strong>I’m the Beneficiary</strong>.</p>

<p>You can also click <strong>Make it Free</strong>, to set the price to 0 MANA and the beneficiary address to a null address. This means that your wearable will be free for the primary sale, but it could be sold for a price in any secondary sale.</p>

<p>After setting the price and beneficiary address, click <strong>Submit</strong>.</p>

<h3 id="publishing-items">Publishing items</h3>

<blockquote>
  <p>The DAO is currently voting on the addition of publication fees for wearables. Until the addition of a fee is decied on, and the size of that fee is determined, users will not be able to publish their wearables. For more information, and to participate in the discussion, visit <a href="https://governance.decentraland.org">governance.decentraland.org</a>.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>After you’ve added all of the relevant metadata to the wearables in your collection, and you’ve set the price and beneficiary address (or made your items free!) you can begin the publication process.</p>

<p>First, navigate to the <a href="https://builder.decentraland.org">Builder</a> and select the <strong>Collections</strong> tab. Select the collection you’d like to publish and click <strong>Publish</strong>.</p>

<p>You might have to authorize the MANA contract to operate MANA on your behalf. By granting this authorization, you are permitting the MANA smart contract to withdraw MANA from your balance to pay the publication fee and to deposit MANA into your account from future sales of your items. Simply check MANA and click <strong>Proceed</strong>. You will have to sign a message from your wallet, but there is no gas fee.</p>

<h4 id="publication-fees">Publication fees</h4>

<p>There is a required fee for publishing items. This fee exists to deter users from publishing an excessive number of wearables in an attempt to “spam” the wearables market.</p>

<p><strong>The fee is a flat rate of 500 MANA per item (not NFT!) in your collection.</strong></p>

<p>For example, if you publish a collection with two items, you will have to pay a fee of 1000 MANA (500 MANA for each item) regardless of the rarity (or how many NFTs can be minted) of those items.</p>

<p>These fees are transferred to the Decentraland DAO, where they are used to help fund the growth of the platform through grants and other initiatives voted on by the greater Decentraland community.</p>

<p><em>Currently, due to the time and resources required to review each collection submitted, the 500 MANA publication fee is non-refundable. If your collection is rejected, you will not receive your 500 MANA back.</em></p>

<p>After reviewing your total fee, click <strong>Next</strong>.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Warning!</strong>
You will not be able to add or remove items in your collection after beginning the publication process. You will be able to see your items within the Decentraland Marketplace, but they will not be able to be bought, sold, or transferred until they have been approved.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>For more detailed information on the publication and approval process, see <a href="/decentraland/publishing-wearables/">Publishing Wearables</a>.</p>

<p>When you are ready, click <strong>Publish</strong> and sign the message when prompted by your wallet.</p>

<h3 id="attributing-collaborators">Attributing collaborators</h3>

<p>If you collaborated with other artists when creating your items, you can add attributions within the Wearables Editor. This can only be done after publishing a collection.</p>

<p>First, navigate to the <a href="https://builder.decentraland.org">Builder</a> and select the <strong>Collections</strong> tab. Select the collection containing the items you want to add attributions to, click the <strong>…</strong> icon next to the <strong>Mint Items</strong> button, and select <strong>Collaborators</strong>.</p>

<p>To add collaborators, simply enter their Ethereum address, and click <strong>Add</strong>. You can add as many collaborators as you want. To remove a collaborator, simply click <strong>Remove</strong> next to the collaborator’s address.</p>

<h3 id="selling-items">Selling items</h3>

<p>After your items are published in a collection and approved by the Curation Committee, they can be sold to other users in the metaverse.</p>

<p>Items can be sold in <strong>primary sales</strong> and <strong>secondary sales</strong>.</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Primary sales</strong> are performed by the Decentraland Store’s smart contract. During a primary sale, the <strong>item is minted automatically</strong>, and it is sold for the price set by you in the Wearable Editor.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Secondary sales</strong> are performed by the Decentraland Marketplace’s smart contract. These occur anytime a user sells an item in the Marketplace <strong>after it has been minted</strong> or <strong>purchased in a primary sale</strong>. Items can be sold for any price in a secondary sale.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>To view items available to purchase in a primary sale, head to the <a href="https://play.decentraland.org/?position=-70%2C0">Decentraland store!</a></p>

<p>To view items available for secondary sales, visit the <a href="https://market.decentraland.org">Decentraland Marketplace.</a></p>

<h3 id="primary-sales">Primary sales</h3>

<p>Primary sales occur when one of your items is purchased for the first time. These sales are only performed by the Decentraland Store’s smart contract.</p>

<p>When a user makes a primary purchase of one of your items, the store <strong>mints the item automatically</strong>, transfers the item to the purchaser, and sends the MANA proceeds to the beneficiary address.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Remember! You do not need to mint your items in order to sell them in primary sales!</p>
</blockquote>

<p>To sell your items via primary sales, begin by navigating to the <a href="https://builder.decentraland.org">Builder</a> and selecting the <strong>Collections</strong> tab.</p>

<h4 id="set-the-price-and-beneficiary-address">Set the price and beneficiary address</h4>

<p>Select the collection you would like to sell, and set the price and beneficiary for each item. The beneficiary address is the address that will receive the MANA resulting from a primary sale.</p>

<p>If the price you set for a primary sale is <strong>“Free”</strong>, users will be able to purchase your items at no cost in the store, but they can resell the item in a secondary sale at any price later on.</p>

<p>You can change the price and beneficiary address for any item in your collection at any time.</p>

<h4 id="enable-primary-sales">Enable primary sales</h4>

<p>Finally, click the On Sale switch and click Turn On in the confirmation window that appears. When this switch is enabled, your collection will be available to purchase within the Decentraland store.</p>

<p><img src="/images/media/wearable-user-guide-images/selling-items-1.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>As long as this switch is turned on, the Decentraland store will automatically mint one of your items whenever a user makes a primary purchase.</p>

<p>This means that it is possible to mint and sell all of your available items until the maximum supply is reached. If you want to save one or more of your items before listing them for sale, you need to manually mint an item to one of your own wallet addresses.</p>

<p>Anyone who purchases one of your items is able to resell it at any time, and at any price, in a secondary sale in Decentraland’s <a href="https://market.decentraland.org">Marketplace</a>.</p>

<p><strong>All primary sales within the Decentraland in-world store are subject to a 2.5% fee. This fee is transferred to the DAO.</strong></p>

<p><strong>If I sell an item via a primary sale, will I receive my MANA on Polygon?</strong><br />
Yes, the proceeds of any items sold on Polygon will reside on the sidechain. You will have to pay a transaction fee if you want to transfer your MANA from the Polygon sidechain to the main Ethereum chain. You can do so from the <a href="https://account.decentraland.org">Accounts</a> page.</p>

<p>If you want to transfer MANA that you’ve earned from a wearable sale on the Polygon to the Ethereum main network, you will have to pay a gas fee at the bridge. For more information on the Polygon sidechain, <a href="https://decentraland.org/blog/announcements/polygon-mana/">please see this blog post</a>.</p>

<h4 id="disabling-primary-sales">Disabling primary sales</h4>

<p>To unlist your items, click the <strong>On Sale</strong> switch to toggle it off. This will only apply to primary sales for your items.</p>

<h3 id="secondary-sales">Secondary sales</h3>

<p>Items can be sold in secondary sales at any time, and for any price, in the Decentraland Marketplace only after:</p>

<ul>
  <li>They have been <strong>minted</strong>, or</li>
  <li>they have been <strong>purchased in a primary sale</strong></li>
</ul>

<p>In other words, anybody who owns an NFT for a wearable can sell it in the Decentraland Marketplace. There are no royalties for wearables sold in secondary sales in Decentraland.</p>

<h3 id="minting-wearables">Minting wearables</h3>

<p>Minting is the process of creating the actual non-fungible tokens (NFTs) based on the items you’ve uploaded to the Wearables Editor.</p>

<p>As with selling items in primary sales, you will not be able to mint any items within a collection until the review process is complete. If your collection is still under review, you will see the tag <strong>“Under Review”</strong> appended to your collection. After it has been reviewed and approved, the tag will change to <strong>“Published”</strong>, and you can begin minting your items manually.</p>

<h4 id="item-rarities">Item rarities</h4>

<p>When you publish a collection, each item in that collection has a <strong>rarity</strong>. This rarity is set by you when you upload an item, and is recorded in a smart contract. Rarities limit the total supply, or <strong>stock</strong>, that you can mint of any particular item.</p>

<p>The available rarities, and the maximum supply provided by each, are:</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th>Rarity</th>
      <th>Limit</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>Unique</td>
      <td>1</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Mythic</td>
      <td>10</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Legendary</td>
      <td>100</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Epic</td>
      <td>1000</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Rare</td>
      <td>5000</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Uncommon</td>
      <td>10000</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Common</td>
      <td>100000</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p> </p>

<p>For example, if you have a collection with one Epic item, then you can only mint up to 1000 NFTs of that item.</p>

<h4 id="the-polygon-sidechain">The Polygon sidechain</h4>

<p>All wearables in Decentraland are minted on the Polygon sidechain. This allows users to mint and transfer items without paying any gas fees (so long as these transactions are conducted solely on the Polygon sidechain).</p>

<h3 id="how-to-manually-mint-your-items">How to manually mint your items</h3>

<p>To mint published items, open the collection containing the items you’d like to mint, and click <strong>Mint Items</strong>.</p>

<p><img src="/images/media/wearable-user-guide-images/minting-items-1.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>You will be shown a modal window containing a list of the items available along with the supply available for each. Remember, the supply is the total number of items you can mint. For example, if your supply reads 0/10, then you have used 0 out of your total supply of 10.</p>

<p><img src="/images/media/wearable-user-guide-images/minting-items-2.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>When minting, you must set the address that will receive the minted items and you must set the number of items you want to mint to that address. You cannot mint more items than are available in the supply available.</p>

<p>If you enter your own address, then the items that are minted will be transferred to your account.</p>

<p>You can “gift” items to anyone you like by entering their address instead of your own under Address.</p>

<p>Remember, these items are minted and transferred to the address entered for free. The price you set for items is only collected in primary sales.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Note: You can currently only mint 50 items per transaction.</p>
</blockquote>

<p><strong>Are there any fees associated with minting items?</strong><br />
No, items are minted on the Matic sidechain, thus removing any fees traditionally associated with minting NFTs on the main Ethereum blockchain.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Decentraland" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How to use the Decentraland Wearables Editor]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/favicon.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/favicon.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Publishing Wearables</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/decentraland/publishing-wearables/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Publishing Wearables" /><published>2021-05-31T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2021-05-31T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/decentraland/publishing-wearables</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/decentraland/publishing-wearables/"><![CDATA[<p>For detailed instructions on how to submit your wearable collection for approval before publication, see the <a href="https://docs.decentraland.org/decentraland/wearables-editor-user-guide/">User Guide</a>. This document explains how the approval process works when publishing wearables, and what criteria is used by the Curation Committee when reviewing wearables. For detailed information on the Curation Committee, <a href="/decentraland/curation-committee/">start here</a>.</p>

<h3 id="the-publication-process">The publication process</h3>

<ol>
  <li>After clicking “Publish” on your completed proposal, it will be submitted to the Curation Committee for approval. Collections pending approval will be flagged as “Under Review”.</li>
  <li>Any collections pending approval from the Curation Committee may not be minted until the approval process is completed.</li>
  <li>Each time you publish a new collection, a post is automatically created on the Decentraland Forum, providing a list and overview of each item in the collection. This Forum post gives the community and the Curation Committee a space to share feedback or request any changes that you need to make before your collection can be approved.</li>
  <li>If there are changes you need to make, the Curation Committee will notify you in the Forum thread for your collection.</li>
  <li>After any needed changes have been made, you can resubmit your collection for approval. (Collections may be reviewed and rejected multiple times before final approval.)</li>
  <li>Once your collection has final approval, you will be notified in the Forum. You will also see a visual indicator in the Wearable Editor next to the approved collection.</li>
  <li>With a successful approval, you can begin minting items in your collection!</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="publication-fees">Publication fees</h3>

<p>There is a required fee for publishing items. This fee was <a href="https://governance.decentraland.org/en/proposal/?id=50092c00-c315-11eb-ac84-1705d1ae4a66">voted in place by the Decentraland DAO</a> This fee exists to deter users from publishing an excessive number of wearables in an attempt to “spam” the wearables market.</p>

<p><strong>The fee is a flat rate of $500 value (paid in MANA) per item (not NFT!) in your collection.</strong></p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Note: Previously it was 500 MANA, with MANA’s value increase, it was lowered to equal $500 in a recent <a href="https://decentraland.org/blog/project-updates/dao-committee-report-11/">DAO vote</a>.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>The calculation examples below use 500 MANA as fee. The actual fee of MANA will be set weekly by the DAO, in order to try and always align with $500 in valuation.</p>

<p>For example, if you publish a collection with two items, you will have to pay a fee of 1000 MANA (500 MANA for each item) regardless of the rarity (or how many NFTs can be minted) of those items.</p>

<p>These fees are transferred to the Decentraland DAO, where they are used to help fund the growth of the platform through grants and other initiatives voted on by the greater Decentraland community.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><strong>Note:</strong> Currently, due to the time and resources required to review each collection submitted, <strong>the 500 MANA publication fee is non-refundable</strong>. If your collection is rejected, you will not receive your 500 MANA back. If your collection is not immediatly approved, the Curation Committee will provide you with suggestions and feedback on how to improve it, but the final acceptance of your collection cannot be guaranteed.</p>
</blockquote>

<h3 id="acceptance-criteria">Acceptance criteria</h3>

<p>Following is an overview of the criteria used by the Curation Committee when determining a collection’s eligibility. Much of this criteria is based on Section 2 of Decentraland’s <a href="https://decentraland.org/content/">Content Policy</a>.</p>

<p>Specifically, wearables may not:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Involve illegality, such as piracy, criminal activity, terrorism, or child pornography</li>
  <li>Infringe third party intellectual property rights</li>
  <li>Contain cruel or hateful imagery that could harm, harass, promote or condone violence against, or that is primarily intended to incite hatred of, animals, or individuals or groups based on race or ethnic origin, religion, nationality, disability, gender, age, veteran status, or sexual orientation/gender identity</li>
  <li>Contain content that is libelous, false, inaccurate, misleading, or invades another person’s privacy</li>
  <li>Breach the Privacy Policy</li>
  <li>Contain any content that promotes or could be construed as primarily intending to evade the limitations described above</li>
</ul>

<p>Please refer to the full Content Policy <a href="https://decentraland.org/content/">here</a> for additional details and definitions. Any submissions that violate the above criteria will be rejected.</p>

<p><strong>In addition to the Content Policy, the committee may reject wearable submissions on the following technical conditions:</strong></p>

<ul>
  <li>It is important that wearables be “skin weighted” correctly so that the avatar animations can be rendered as expected. Wearables without correct skin weighting will be rejected.</li>
  <li>Wearables must preserve avatar UV mapping to ensure that user-selected skin tones can be rendered as expected.</li>
  <li>The dimensions of eyebrow, eye, and mouth textures should not exceed 256 by 256px, and these textures must include an alpha channel for transparency.</li>
  <li>
    <p>Wearables with a disproportionate number of triangles and textures may be rejected. Wearables with too many triangles and textures can result in poor performance and a bad experience for users, so creators should avoid exceeding the following guidelines when creating wearables:</p>

    <ul>
      <li>No more than 1.5K triangles per wearable (except skin category)</li>
      <li>No more than 500 triangles per accessories</li>
      <li>No more than 2 textures (at a resolution of 512x512px or lower) per wearable. All textures must be square.</li>
      <li>No more than 5k triangles for skin category and 5 textures (at a resolution of 512x512px or lower). All textures must be square.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Wearables may not contain duplicate items within a collection. (Each item within a collection must be unique.)</li>
  <li>Wearables may not mimic or copy other wearables that have already been published.</li>
  <li>Wearables with misleading categories may be rejected; for example, a hat that is categorized as a lower body item.</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Decentraland" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A description of the publication and approval process for Decentraland wearables]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/favicon.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/images/favicon.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>